My apologies for the wait.
You even had a change of clothes for me.
Thank you ever so much.
Have you made your decision?
Indeed.
Pride, who was it that rescued me from the pub?
Val!
Come over here, right now!
What?! Get off my back!
You don't need me for anything!
Whoa, Mistress!
You shoulda told me when the pretty boy woke up!
Damn it!
'Cause this is what happens!
Oh, that's right.
I gave him permission to ignore decorum,
but only while he was keeping an eye on Leon.
At any other time, he's bound
to show deference by the fealty contract.
It was you?
You have my deepest gratitude
for everything you've done.
I don't know what would have become of me without your help.
I will be sure to repay you for this kindness.
No, I didn't choose to do it.
I was ordered to by my mistress!
Hey, Mistress! Gimme a break already!
You have permission to ignore decorum with Prince Leon.
I only saved you 'cause my mistress ordered me to.
Couldn't give a crap what happens to you!
That doesn't matter.
You saved me, and that fact is undeniable.
I truly am grateful to you.
And thank you to you two, as well.
I'll make sure to repay you in kind.
Now that's a genuine smile, right?
Let's go to the castle.
Every day's unique, you get one chance at it
So you'd better make it count
When people flaunt morality
You've gotta beware they've got their own agenda
Somewhere in your head, there's a voice that's messin' with ya
Don't ever let it turn you 'round
It can't even blow all that hot air it's full of
Get yourself in gear and live however you wanna
Live so fast that the claws of despair will languish in your dust
And you'll be the one with an agenda that they'll all see as just
Keep on shouldering the world around you
Keep on doubting every thought that's bound you
If things go awry, keep pushing through
And know that everything'll work in the end
If you find it's in your power to change the world
I'm sure you can make the future bright
We'll blaze on ahead until we track down the route we want to take
We'll keep trying every door until we find one that goes our way
The Cruel Queen
Makes a Declaration
I do apologize for the sudden visit,
Your Majesty, King Gregorio.
Please excuse my intrusion.
I would like to explain the events leading up to this visit,
but before that, I have one request to make.
Would you please summon Prince Erwin
and Prince Homer to join us right now?
I really would like to see them.
Well, as it happens...
I'm sure my sons would love to meet with Leon's fiancée.
Oh my.
Don't get the wrong idea, Your Majesty.
As it currently stands, I am not here as Leon's fiancée,
but as a representative of our queen.
My mother has formally authorized me
to act in this capacity.
I will ask you once more.
Please bring Prince Erwin and Prince Homer here.
Elder Brother!
You're home safe!
It is an honor to meet the both of you,
Prince Erwin and Prince Homer.
Thank you for taking excellent care of my darling fiancé.
By the way, Your Majesty...
Before we address the core of the matter,
I know Leon has something to say about his situation.
Father.
Last night, I woke up sitting
at a pub in town, unable to move,
before being rescued by Pride.
It was all part of a plot by Erwin and Homer to frame me.
They came to my room and made me drink spiked wine,
then abandoned me at the pub.
Wait a minute, Leon!
I think there's been a misunderstanding!
Homer is right!
We only insisted on sharing some wine last night
because we were saddened to part ways with you.
But we'd never drug it! That's a wild accusation!
Except it's not.
Pride's subordinates rescued me from the pub.
They determined that I had been drugged.
Well, that proves nothing!
It's all just rubbish cooked up by Princess Pride!
The Kingdom of Freesia is trying to pull the wool over your eyes!
He's right! Freesia has been
buttering you up, Elder Brother.
Now that they're spouting this nonsense, I'd imagine
they'll use it as an excuse to declare war on our nation!
Besides, isn't it awfully convenient
that they somehow found you just in the nick of time?
It's painfully obvious.
The Kingdom of Freesia has fabricated this entire farce,
either by hiring some mercenary kidnapper,
or even by convincing you to play along, Elder Brother.
Erwin, Homer...
I thought I'd made myself clear!
I warned you to clean up your act before it was too late!
My sons have done an intensely foolish thing.
I deeply apologize for their insolence.
In the name of King Gregorio of Anemone,
Erwin Adonis Coronaria...
Homer Adonis Coronaria...
I hereby strip you both
of your royal titles and all rights therein!
Arrest them!
Yes, sir!
Let me go!
You ruffians!
Who besides me or Homer
is fit to inherit the throne, Father?!
Your Majesty.
I had a premonition.
You have something to discuss with me.
Or rather, originally you'd meant
to discuss it with my mother, yes?
You wish to discuss the cancellation of my engagement with Prince Leon Adonis Coronaria.
Isn't that right?
In order to officially return
Prince Leon's right to the throne.
How could you know that?!
Crown Princess Pride, at this time—
Wait a moment.
Please, listen to what I have to say first.
As representative of the queen, acting on her behalf,
I am here to request the immediate dissolution
of my engagement to Prince Leon Adonis Coronaria.
For that is what the Kingdom of Freesia wishes.
Ridiculous!
Our brother is the perfect prince!
There is no reason for Freesia
to want the engagement to be dissolved!
He's right!
But there is a reason.
It's because the original purpose
of our engagement no longer exists.
The engagement was first proposed as a way
to solidify the alliance between our two kingdoms.
And furthermore, to put that alliance
on display for our neighboring countries.
But I had a premonition.
I saw the future of the Anemone Kingdom,
which had fallen to the verge of ruin
after Prince Leon left.
Prince Leon, your kingdom needs you.
If you wish to become a ruler who loves and cherishes
their citizens as I do, then we shall be sworn friends.
There is no need for an engagement.
Sworn friends...
Precisely.
As long as our friendship holds firm,
there could be no greater proof our lands' alliance.
The only thing we wish from the Anemone Kingdom
is to retain the equal partnership that we've had until now!
And solidify it further!
Our alliance would never falter
in the face of a mere cancelled engagement.
And as the Crown Princess, I will make sure of it...
with my sworn friend, Prince Leon.
And I too. Without fail.
You'll regret this, Leon! You're a joke!
A soulless puppet like you can never become king!
You're a dumb patsy who never realized
what Homer and I were up to!
You don't have what it takes to rule a kingdom!
This place will fall apart in no time with you in charge!
Then you'll look back and realize the truth!
That I was the one worthy of being king!
I'm obviously superior to a pathetic bastard like you
who can't live without being loved by the masses!
Shut your mouth!
Now you listen here.
Prince Leon has all the qualities needed to become a great king.
He is not a puppet or anything of the sort.
He loves his people more than himself
and strives to live up to their expectations.
He's a vital asset who has dedicated himself to being a worthy king.
You think this land will fall apart with him in charge?
In my premonition, that's exactly what happened
after Prince Leon left and you became king.
Under your reign, the people fled the country
to escape poverty, hampering your trade relations.
Even the royal family declined into such a state
that one could hardly imagine that
the Kingdom of Anemone had once prospered.
Elder Sister...
And worst of all, the instant things started looking bad,
you came to Freesia begging for Prince Leon's help!
That's how things play out for them in the game.
Despite being the source of Leon's downfall,
they shamelessly come to him for help over and over.
They beg him to come back.
And then...
They have the gall to ask him:
"Do you not care what happens to our people?!"
This infuriates Leon, who sends them packing.
Afterwards, he breaks down in Tiara's arms
in one of the game's most heartbreaking scenes.
Ever since his brothers were young, they'd harbored
a sense of inferiority towards Crown Prince Leon.
That's why they spread rumors about him,
resulting in Leon being forced to marry
into the Freesian royal family.
However, the king later learns the truth...
and upon deciding that Leon should be
the heir to the throne after all, he warns them:
You best clean up your act before it's too late!
But that doesn't stop them.
Determined to force Leon out of contention for the throne,
they get him drunk and drop him off at a pub.
That alone makes them utter scumbags,
but it gets worse...
You witch.
Just how much did your premonition show you?!
I know all sorts of things.
For example, the fact His Majesty
already knew of your wrongdoings,
and told you he would make Leon
heir to the throne a few days ago.
Remember this.
From here on,
no matter what punishment you face...
if you ever pose a threat to this kingdom or
my sworn friend Prince Leon again, I will not stand for it.
If you dare to cross that line, then you will be making
a personal enemy of Pride Royal Ivy.
And I will carry out fitting retribution myself.
As if some lucky bitch born into
a queendom is worth anything!
After all this, do you think you're
worth enough to call yourselves royalty?
Leon was racked by so much grief
at the start of the game...
because all of the Anemonians who'd been
in the pub with him were sentenced to death.
Even worse, Pride had ordered Leon to kill them himself.
To top it off, it was his brothers who offered the innocent citizens to Pride as "criminals" in the first place.
Soon after Leon moves to Freesia, the king falls ill
and dies, causing his brothers to inherit the throne.
They proceed to make an absolute mess of everything
and then have the gall to ask Leon to fix it.
They pressure Tiara to help them
convince him to return to Anemone,
and even kidnap Tiara to use as a hostage
and threaten Leon into coming back home.
We all carry the duty of royalty,
so I can't find it in myself to cut them any slack right now.
Tell me something.
What was it you hoped to do after taking the throne?
Because if your citizens weren't
the first thing on your mind, then that says it all.
You have no right to deny someone
with as noble a heart as Prince Leon.
I've overstepped my bounds.
Elder Sister, are you all right?
I'm fine.
Pride...
Thank you.
Prince Leon, please be proud.
Please love. Please wish for things.
Your pure heart and this country that you love so much...
It's all so very beautiful.
He's gone through so much suffering these past few days because of me.
Despite being tormented by the love of his country,
he kept it all bottled inside to maintain appearances.
He played the role of the sweet prince
and suppressed all his true feelings.
All while smiling and whispering words of love to me.
But in reality, he was full of more
pain and regret than anyone.
Thank goodness.
I'm so glad I could give him back
his precious Kingdom of Anemone.
And return him to his rightful place within it.
Crown Prince Leon Adonis Coronaria.
Do you swear, in sickness and in health,
for richer or for poorer,
to love the people of your country,
to adore and protect them,
and to dedicate yourself to improving their lives?
I do!
Your Majesty King Gregorio,
I have one more thing to ask of you.
Allow me to introduce my younger brother
and the knights who helped to make this right.
Please do them the honor of shaking
their hands and greeting them.
Of course.
I will do the same!
Everything should be okay now.
In the game, the king had to make it known that Leon
had been punished for the commotion at the pub
and exiled him from the country.
But as soon as Leon was sent to Freesia, the king fell ill and passed away.
However, Arthur's special ability
is the power to heal anything in creation.
Based on the look he just gave,
I'm sure the king's sickness has already been cured.
Princess Pride...
You can keep calling me Pride
like you have up to now, Prince Leon.
We are sworn friends, after all.
Then, please call me Leon.
I'd be happier that way.
All right, Leon.
I look forward to seeing you again.
You do?
Yes, I do.
Okay.
Your Highness.
Go ahead.
Pride...
I am forever in your debt.
If you or Freesia ever need anything,
the Kingdom of Anemone will...
No, I will come running to your aid, no matter what.
Let us keep in touch.
I will come see you as often as needed.
And I will be waiting for you
here in my beloved country, always.
Farewell, my darling fiancée.
You are my first love.
P-Princess Pride?!
Elder Sister!
F-F-First love?!
Pride? Me?!
Oh, jeez!
That's the incredible seductiveness
of the "flirt" archetype from the first ORL game for you!
The Most Heretical Last Boss Queen:
From Villainess to Savior.
Episode 5:
"The Cruel Queen Takes Notice, and is Noticed".
The Cruel Queen Takes Notice, and is Noticed